Ivan Ivani, PhD

Address: Radnicka 16, 21000 Novi Sad, Serbia

Mobile: +381642362210

E-mail: <u>jasamivani@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/iivani</u>
Date of birth: <u>6th February 1986</u>



I am a Data Scientist with a scientific background in bioinformatics and over five years of experience in data analytics within an international organization across various contexts. I have managed small data teams and implemented complex projects. I am keen to bring my international experience, problem-solving mindset, and enthusiasm to a new and challenging environment, particularly focusing on financial consulting and treasury management.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Analyst User Experience R&D – Continental – Serbia

Oct 2023 - Present

- Established and maintained an efficient data management system for optical experiments and production data, supporting R&D teams globally.
- Specialized in preparing graphs and processing diverse datasets from optical experiments and production End-of-Line (EOL) plants.
- Created interactive dashboards using Python and PowerBI to facilitate seamless collaboration and informed decision-making.
- Contributed to the team's expansion and development of Data Science infrastructure and streamlined data processes.

Data Analytics and Management Lead Protection Unit – ICRC – Jerusalem and Caracas

Jan 2021 - Jun 2023

- Handled highly sensitive personal data, ensuring secure and ethical management.
- Prepared intricate reports and infographics for strategic decision-making.
- Led small teams, fostering collaboration and efficient data handling, and trained colleagues in complex SQL and Python data processes.
- Acted as a Project Manager for the Jerusalem Delegation, steering the Family Visit Program through feasibility and planning phases.

Data Analyst Protection Unit – ICRC – Belgrade, Geneva and Damascus

Jul 2018 - Dec 2020

- Created an automated dashboard for the Syrian delegation that integrates external information sources into the ICRC PCP framework, mapping events and providing statistical feedback.
- Developed a dashboard at HQ visualizing ETD request flows over time and country, aiding in strategic planning.
- Supported delegates and operations with reports and analyses, enhancing data-driven decision-making.
- Evaluated and improved the quality of Prot6 databases and infrastructure.

Research Scientist Institute for Research in Biomedicine - IRB Barcelona, Spain

Jan 2010 - Jun 2017

Intern Scientist Stanford University and Pfizer, USA

May 2015 - Aug 2015

- I spent time as a visiting researcher in the group of Eric Kool, working on a project of software optimization Worked on software optimization for computational biology simulations in collaboration with the pharma industry.
- Conducted experiments on short DNA sequences and parameterized molecular dynamics software based on experimental findings.

EDUCATION

PhD in Bioinformatics (cum laude)

Dec 2016

Universitat de Barcelona, Spain

MSc in Biophysics (Top 2% of the class)

Jun 2010

Charles University in Prague, Czechia

BSc in Physics Charles University in Prague, Czechia Aug 2008

SKILLS AND AWARDS

Languages

• English (Fluent), Czech (Fluent), Spanish (Fluent), Russian (Conversational), French (basic), Serbian (Native).

Tools

- Programming: Python, SQL
- · Visualization: Matlab, Tableau, Power Bl.
- · Office tools: Excel, Power Point, Word, Minitab

Awards and honours

- EMBO fellowship, Stanford, USA
- IUBMB Young Researcher fellowship, Taipei, Taiwan
- FEBS Young Researcher fellowship, St. Petersburg, Russia
- IRB Barcelona PhD fellowship, Barcelona, Spain
- Charles University scholarship (top 5% of students), Prague, Czechia

HOBBIES

I am a nature lover, a sportsman and a fan of climbing. I love travelling, gastronomy and discovering new things. I enjoy constructive discussions and a collaborative environment.